（うずまきナルト）はあーっ！
He has grown.
（うちはイタチ）
確かに 成長はしている
（ナルト）せやあーっ！
But... he's still not good enough.
（イタチ）が まだ甘い
（ナルト）ううっ
Damn it! This hurts.
（ナルト）クソ いってえ
But this is... a Genjutsu...
I've got to overpower it!
でも これは幻術げんじゅつだ
打ち勝つんだってばよ
（ナルト）う… ん？
Naruto...
（うちはサスケ）ナルト
（ナルト）あっ
Naruto...!
（サスケ）ナルト
（ナルト）サ… サスケ
Sasuke...?
Long time no see, Naruto...
（サスケ）久しぶりだな ナルト
（ナルト）うわあっ！
ううっ
なっ
ぐっ うう…
うっ！
I failed to kill you back then,
you see...
（サスケ）あのときは
殺しそこねたからな
（ナルト）ぐ…
You're finished!
（サスケ）終わりだ
（ナルト）う… くっ
Why...?
（春野はるのサクラ）どうして
Why... didn't you stop Sasuke-kun?
I believed in you...
（サクラ）どうして
サスケ君を止めてくれなかったの
信じてたのに
（ナルト）ハッ
You couldn't protect your friends...
（はたけカカシ）お前は
仲間を守れなかったじゃないか
期待していたのに 失望したよ
I was counting on you...
I'm so disappointed.
You always...
（我愛羅があら）
いつも お前ばかりが得をする
You always come out ahead...
（ナルト）ハッ
You always... achieve happiness...
（我愛羅）
お前ばかりが 幸せを勝ちとる
（ナルト）うっ ううっ
It's a Genjutsu...
（ナルト）幻術だ
I know...
it's a Genjutsu, but...!
幻術だって 分かってるのに…
Naruto... I believed in you...
ナルト 信じてたのに
I'm so disappointed...
Naruto...
（カカシ）失望したよ ナルト
（我愛羅）いつも お前ばかりが
It's... always you...
今度こそ とどめだ
This time... I'll finish you off!
Damn it! Damn it! Damn it!
（ナルト）クソ クソ クソ
I know it's a Genjutsu, but...!
幻術だって 分かってるのに
（ナルト）くっ
Say, say!
（ナルト）あのさ あのさあ
I get the part where you temporarily
stop the flow of Chakra
えーと チャクラの流れを
いったん止めて
and use a greater Chakra
than the enemy's
相手のチャクラを上回る力で
チャクラの流れを乱す...
to disrupt the flow of Chakra.
ってとこまでは 分かったけど
But what if that still doesn't work...?
もし それでもダメだったら？
What should I do if
I can't break the Genjutsu?!
幻術が解けなかったら
一体どうすればいいんだってばよ
（自来也じらいや）ふむ…
At that time... you give up!
（自来也）そのときは 諦める
ええっ
What?!
You'd have to accept you were
out of luck, and just give up.
（自来也）運がなかったと
諦めるしかないのォ
That's the way it goes
with Genjutsu.
幻術とは そういうものだからのォ
No way...
そんな…
あ～あ
Then what was the point of falling
into the river
じゃ なんのために 俺は
川に落ちて
ずぶぬれになってんだってばよ
and getting drenched?
However... if you've got
your comrades with you...
じゃが 仲間と一緒に
行動をしとるなら
there just might be a chance!
手がないこともない
その仲間に己の体に触れてもらい
Get them to touch you and
funnel their Chakra into you.
チャクラを
流し込んでもらうんだのォ
そうすることで 己の中の
チャクラの流れを乱してもらう
By doing that, you have the flow
of Chakra inside you disrupted...
それで 幻術は解ける
Then... you can break the Genjutsu.
ハア ハア ハア…
I believed in you...
信じてたのに
（カカシ）失望したよ
I'm so disappointed...
（我愛羅）お前ばかりが
It's always you...
I'll finish you off!
とどめだ
Naruto!
（サクラ）ナルト
Sakura-chan...
（ナルト）サクラちゃん
Naruto!
（カカシ）ナルト
Kakashi-sensei...
（ナルト）カカシ先生
Naruto!
（我愛羅）ナルト
Gaara...
（ナルト）我愛羅
Naruto!
（サスケ）ナルト
Sasuke...
（ナルト）サスケ
ハア ハア ハア…
S-Somebody...
give me Chakra...
（ナルト）だが 俺にチャクラは…
K-Kakashi-sensei... Sakura-chan...
（ナルト）
カカシ先生 サクラちゃん
Please... give me Chakra!
あれ？ チャクラは…
うっ
You okay, Naruto?!
（カカシ）大丈夫か ナルト
What happened to me...?
俺ってば
You were caught in a Genjutsu!
（サクラ）幻術よ
But you're okay now!
でも もう大丈夫
We poured our Chakra in you
and broke the Genjutsu!
チャクラを流し込んで
幻術を解いたから
（ナルト）う…
Where's... his Shadow Clone...?
あいつの影分身は？
Shadow Clone...?
He's using no such thing.
（チヨ）影分身じゃと？
（チヨ）あやつは影分身など
使つこうておらんぞ
You suddenly started running
あんた いきなり走り出して
and shot off your Rasengan
with nothing around.
何もないところで
螺旋丸らせんがん ぶっ放したのよ
Don't you remember?
覚えてないの？
うっ
はあーっ！ 螺旋丸！
Rasengan!
Then back then...
I was already in the Genjutsu...
（ナルト）
じゃあ あのときには もう
This guy's using more
than just a Vision Jutsu...
こやつ 瞳術どうじゅつだけではないな
（カカシ）さて いよいよ本丸だ
Now, it's about time for the main event.
気合い入れてよ ナルト
Get it together, Naruto!
あ…
Hey! Get a grip!
ほら しっかりしろ
Naruto, I'll show you how it's done.
（カカシ）
ナルト 俺が手本を見せてやる
（ナルト）う…
♪～
A voice heard in the distance gives me a hint.
tooku de kikoeru koe wo hinto ni
One by one like-minded people are standing up.
hitori mata hitori tachiagaru doushi
Lets overturn all the everyday, monotonous things.
kurikaesu dake no fudan doori kutsugaesu
I'm ready, are you ready?
junbi iize are you ready
A shiver spreads through my body, violently ringing stomping.
karadajuu furuwasu shindou ni hageshiku uchinarase yo stomping
Constantly stirring in me, it calls me.
taezu tsuki ugokasu call me
Catching that unchanging, never wavering story, Come on!
kawarazu yuru ga nutsukamu story come on
Everybody stand up! Today's the best time to get up!
everybody stand up agero kyou ichiban no jikan da
Before my eyes you still don't stop, speed hunter.
me ni mo tomaranu speed hunter
Everyone is a victim to that attraction, Yeah! (Come on!)
daremo ga mina toriko kanban yeah come on
Everybody Hands up! It's the highly anticipated Hero's Come Back!
everybody hands up matashita na hero's come back
Hold up your fingers and count down.
zujou kazoe yubi oru count down
Let's go, 3-2-1 make some noise!
ikuze 3-2-1 make some noise
Are you ready for a few risks?
hey yo whoa tashou no risuku wa kakugo desho
You have to get up no matter how many times you fall. (Get it on!)
nanka korundatte tatsu get it on
It's not some conspiracy, just a paper-thin session
nare ai ja nai ze kami hitoe no sesshon
The pent up feelings turn into a crystal.
irikunda kanjou kidzukiageta kesshou
The rising cheers will become your courage.
wakiagaru kansei ga yuuki tonaru
So stand up now, no matter how much pain you feel.
tachiagareba ima ijou kurushimi tomonau
But in the end I'm sure you'll laugh.
soredemo saigo wa kitto warau
Everything will be swept away in victory and cheer.
subete sarau shouri to kansei
Everybody stand up! Today's the best time to get up!
everybody stand up agero kyou ichiban no jikan da
Before my eyes you still don't stop, speed hunter.
me ni mo tomaranu speed hunter
Everyone is a victim to that attraction, Yeah! (Come on!)
daremo ga mina toriko kanban yeah come on
Everybody Hands up! It's the highly anticipated Hero's Come Back!
everybody hands up matashita na hero's come back
～♪
Hold up your fingers and count down.
zujou kazoe yubi oru count down
Let's go, 3-2-1 make some noise!
ikuze 3-2-1 make some noise
Fire Style...
（イタチ）火遁(かとん)･鳳仙火(ほうせんか)の術
Phoenix Flower Jutsu!
He dodged it!
かわした
（カカシ）次 来るぞ
Here comes the next attack!
Fire Style: Fireball Jutsu!
（イタチ）火遁･豪火球(ごうかきゅう)の術
The Secret Weapon is Called...!
Lightning Blade!
（カカシ）雷切らいきり
（イタチ）あ…
Rasengan!
（ナルト）螺旋丸！
（サクラ）あっ！
Did they get him...?
やったか？
Naruto!
ナルト！
I see... He sure has learned
an interesting Jutsu.
（イタチ）なるほど
おもしろい術を
身につけてきたものだ
However...
だが
（ナルト）ハア ハア ハア…
Damn it! I guess
it won't be that easy.
（ナルト）クソ
やっぱ 簡単にはいかねえってばよ
I thought I totally got behind him
カカシ先生の雷切を陽動に使って
using Kakashi-sensei's
Lightning Blade as a diversion...
完全に あいつの
裏をかいたはずなのに
The Sharingan sure is a problem.
写輪眼しゃりんがんは やっかいだ
He can instantly foresee
what I'm going to do.
一瞬で こっちの動きが
先読みされちまう
Not again!
（ナルト）またかよ
This isn't going to work without
a combination attack with Kakashi-sensei.
（ナルト）やっぱり
カカシ先生との連携は外せねえ
On top of that, I'll need a powerful Jutsu
that can beat him in one shot...
その上で
１発でヤツを倒せる強力な術
I'll have to try out that Jutsu...
あれを試すしかねえってばよ
Where's Naruto...?
Is he okay?
（サクラ）
ナルトはどこ？ 無事なの？
What?! Is this one of his Genjutsu?!
何？ あいつの幻術？
A Hidden Mist Jutsu?!
霧隠きりがくれの術？
Don't worry! It's one of Kakashi's Jutsu.
（チヨ）案ずるでない
（サクラ）あ…
カカシの術じゃ
Then...
それでは
More importantly,
the mist is getting thicker!
それより 霧が濃くなってゆくぞ
Don't avert your attention away
from his presence!
ヤツの気配から目を離すでないぞよ
R-Right!
あ… はい
The Hidden Mist Jutsu...
（イタチ）霧隠れの術？
It's indeed an effective Jutsu
幻術にかかりづらくするためには
確かに効果的だが
for making it difficult
to cast a Genjutsu...
But it's meaningless against me,
who possesses the Sharingan...
写輪眼を持つ私の前では
意味をなさない
Could we please stop this childish game
of hide and seek, Kakashi-san?!
（イタチ）かくれんぼなんて
子どもじみた遊びは
やめにしませんか
カカシさん
I suppose we could...
（カカシ）それもそうだな
Fire Style: Fireball Jutsu!
（イタチ）火遁･豪火球の術
I get it! Awesome, Kakashi-sensei!
（ナルト）なるほど
さすが カカシ先生だってばよ
The Fireball Jutsu...
（カカシ）豪火球…
しかし さっきから 何か…
But I noticed earlier,
something's off...
（カカシ）ハッ！
うっ
Don't tell me, Kakashi-sensei...
is under his Genjutsu?!
まさか カカシ先生 幻術に？
（ナルト）フッ
（イタチ）
さすが 術の使いどころがうまい
Just as I'd expect...
You sure know how to use a Jutsu...
Since you hid yourself temporarily
using the Earth Style,
いったん土遁どとんで姿を消したので
I didn't notice in time...
気づくのが遅れてしまった
No wonder...
my Genjutsu's having no effect.
どうりで
幻術に手応えがないはずだ
This is a Shadow Clone.
これは影分身
（干柿ほしがき鬼鮫きさめ）うう…
He's fast...!
（鬼鮫）速い
Is that...?
（テンテン）あれって
Yeah...
（日向ひゅうがネジ）ああ
（ロック･リー）うん 勝負ありです
Game over!
うわ
Asakujaku!
（マイト･ガイ）朝孔雀あさくじゃく！
ふっ！
（ガイ）ハア ハア ハア…
ハア ハア ハア…
Looks like it's over...
（パックン）終わったようじゃな
Take him out, my Shadow Clone
and all, Naruto!
（カカシ）
俺の影分身ごとやれ ナルト
- I know!
（ナルト）分かってるってばよ
Huh? Improve my Rasengan?
（ナルト）あ？ 螺旋丸の改良？
That's right...
（自来也）うん そうじゃ
螺旋丸なら
もう十分に使えるってばよ
I can already use the Rasengan
well enough!
More importantly,
teach me some new Jutsu!
それよりさ
新しい術を教えてくれよ
ハハッ お前のォ
Listen, you...
Do you think the Rasengan
you use now is good enough...?
今の螺旋丸で十分だと
思っとるのか？
Think back to when you fought
大蛇丸おろちまるの連れの眼鏡と
やりあったときのことを
that four-eyed guy
who was with Orochimaru.
思い出してみろ
（ナルト）えっ
うう…
だっ うわっ
（薬師やくしカブト）フッ
I don't know what kind
of Jutsu you've learned.
（カブト）
どんな術を覚えたか知らないが
But you can't hit me with
that large of a motion.
そんな大きなモーションで
僕に当てることなどできない
う… くっ
This won't work...
It's too tough to hit a moving target...
（ナルト）ダメだってば
動く相手じゃ 簡単には当たんねえ
And then what did you do next?!
（自来也）そこで
次にお前のとった行動は
これで 逃がさないですむ
You won't get away now...
はあーっ！
（カブト）うわあっ！
Are you going to get
your hand cut open
（自来也）あのときと同じように
each time you face off
against an enemy?
敵に立ち向かうたびに
手に穴をあけるつもりかのォ
（ナルト）うう…
That's exactly why
I need a new Jutsu!
だからさ そのためにも新しい術を
Are you being serious?
お前 それ本気で言っとるのか
Don't tell me you've forgotten?
まさか 忘れたわけでは
あるまいのォ
The Rasengan is a Jutsu
the Fourth Hokage left behind for us!
螺旋丸は あの四代目火影ほかげの
残した術だということをのォ
Oh... Uh... Well...
I haven't forgotten it or anything...
あ…
わ… う… 忘れてる… う…
（自来也）フフフフ まあよい
Fair enough.
The Rasengan is a Jutsu completed
by the Fourth Hokage.
螺旋丸は四代目が完成させた術だ
それを今度は
お前自身の術にしてみろのォ
Now you should try
to make it your own.
Improve the Rasengan and make it
into your own original Jutsu.
螺旋丸に さらに磨きをかけ
お前 オリジナルの術に
改良するんだ
Huh?!
（ナルト）あ？
My own original Jutsu...
俺のオリジナルの術
That's right.
そうだ
Use that massive Chakra
of yours
お前のその膨大なチャクラを
利用して
to make the Rasengan
easier to hit an enemy with.
螺旋丸を
さらに敵に当てやすくする
It'll be a Jutsu possible only
through that massive Chakra.
そのチャクラ量だからこそ
なせる術
It'll be your own original Rasengan!
まさしく お前だけの
オリジナル螺旋丸
ヘヘッ
My own original Rasengan!
俺だけの オリジナル螺旋丸
And in order to improve
the power of the Rasengan,
それには まず威力を上げるために
you need to build up
much more Chakra.
より多くのチャクラを
練り込む必要がある
The training will once again be rough!
また つらい修業になる
しかし それが完成すれば
But if you complete it,
it will become your strongest weapon.
お前の最強の武器になるだろうのォ
We'll call it...
名付けて…
- Giant... Rasengan!
大玉螺旋丸！
A-Amazing...!
す… すごい
Ooh... He's...!
おおっ こヤツ…
What... was up with that smile?
なんだ？ 今の笑いは
I do get the feeling I fought him
somewhere before, but...
確かに どこかで戦ったような
気もするんだがな
You really don't remember?
本当に覚えていないのですか
It looked like he knew
a lot about you, Guy-sensei...
相手のほうは ガイ先生のこと
よく知ってるみたいでしたけど？
What's going on...?
どうなっているんだ
（ガイ）あ…
H-He's...
こ… こいつは
う…
Wh-What's this...?
こ… これは
While we were fighting,
I felt like something wasn't right...
（カカシ）途中から
変な感じはしていたんだが
What do you mean?!
どういうことだってばよ
It's one of... their Jutsu or something...
ヤツらの術か何かね
He's...
（チヨ）こヤツ
What is this?
What in the world does this mean?
（リー）これは 一体
どういうことなんでしょうか
I don't know...
分からん
But... there's one thing I can say...
だが ひとつ言えるのは
I don't know this man, after all!
この男… やっぱり知らん
Do you know him...?
（カカシ）
知ってらっしゃるんですか
Yes...
ああ
It's Yuura...
He's a Jonin from our village...
由良ゆうら うちの里の上忍じょうにんだ
When I look up at the sky.
sora wo miagereba
♪～
The stars, see, are sparkling.
hoshitachi ga hora matataiteru
Each giving off its own light.
kono hoshi no hitotachi mitai ni
Like the people on this planet.
samazama na hikari wo hanatte
Yeah, so among them, I too,
sono naka de boku mo
want to shine particularly bright.
hitokiwa kagayaite itain da
I close my eyes and make a vow in my heart,
me wo tojite kokoro ni chikau
and entrust my dreams to that shooting star.
nagareboshi ni yume wo takushite
I'm in my usual park.
koko wa itsumo no kouen
I can see the night scenery on the slide.
yakei ga mieru suberidai no ue
That's been my special seat for years.
mukashi kara boku no tokutouseki
Whenever I'm worried about something, I come here.
nayami ga areba koko ni kurun desu
Just like then, I'm on my way to my dreams.
ano koro no mama yume no tochuu de
But unable to fulfil them.
ima de kanaerarezu ni irun desu
Maybe this is the end of the line.
moshikashite koko ga mou shuuten
There are days when I say weak things like that.
nante yowane wo haite shimaisou na hi mo aru
But every time, I remember.
demo sono tabi ni omoidasu
That starry sky where I looked for a shooting star.
nagareboshi wo sagashite ano hoshizora
The wish I made when I was little hasn't changed even now.
chiisana koro no negaigoto ima mukashi mo kawaranai mama
When I look up at the sky.
sora wo miagereba
The stars, see, are sparkling.
hoshitachi ga hora matataiteru
Each giving off its own light.
kono hoshi no hitotachi mitai ni
Like the people on this planet.
samazama na hikari wo hanatte
Yeah, so among them, I too,
sono naka de boku mo
want to shine particularly bright.
hitokiwa kagayaite itain da
I close my eyes and make a vow in my heart,
me wo tojite kokoro ni chikau
～♪
and entrust my dreams to that shooting star.
nagareboshi ni yume wo takushite
Next Episode
真実の探究は
常に危険と隣り合わせである
Seeking the truth always involves
putting one's life at risk.
謎を追い
砂漠に踏み込んだ我々を
As we pursued mystery,
the desert's blazing sun, sand storms
待ち受けていたのは
しゃく熱の太陽 視界を遮る砂嵐
猛毒サソリの洗礼だった
and poisonous scorpions
awaited us.
だが 我々は歴史の闇に
ついにメスを入れることになる
However, we will end up reforming
the darkness of history.
想像を超えた石像の秘密が
今 明らかに
Secrets about the statue beyond
our imagination will now be revealed!
ネクスト イット
It's on next!
忍界にんかいロマン 不思議ランド
巨大石像の謎を追え
"Pursue romance
in the Shinobi world,
mysterious lands,
and the mystery of the giant statue!"
それ 歴代風影かぜかげの
石像じゃん？
That's just a statue of the previous Kazekage.
The Secret of the Jinchuriki
次回
「人柱力の秘密」
Next episode: "The Secret of Jinchuriki"
Notable People in the Leaf Village
（ナルト）木(こ)ノ葉(は) 人物短冊帖
Notable people in the Leaf Village
In this feature, we introduce
famous people from the village.
里の有名人を紹介する
このコーナー
Today, we'll be introducing...
今回 紹介するのはと…
Hi-ya, sorry to keep you waiting!
（自来也）
あいや 待たせたのォ
I'm the one and only Jiraiya-sama, the sexy man
who strikes fear in the hearts of men!
泣く子も黙る色男 自来也様たあ
あ わしのことよ
Hey, Pervy Sage! Don't be upstaging me!
（ナルト）やい エロ仙人
俺より目立つんじゃねえ
Don't be such a stick-in-the-mud.
Get to my introduction.
堅いこと言うなっての
ほれ さっさと紹介せんか
Okay, fine. Umm, he's one of the Leafs
vaunted three legendary Sannin.
（ナルト）分かったよ
えー 木ノ葉が誇る
伝説の三忍さんにんの１人
Right, right.
（自来也）ふんふん
He's a powerhouse who had
the Third as his master
（ナルト）三代目を師に
四代目を弟子に持つ実力者
and the Fourth as his apprentice.
Right, right.
（自来也）ふんふん
（ナルト）
それから カカシ先生が愛読している
つまんねえ本の作者
And he's the author of the boring books
Kakashi-sensei's always reading.
（自来也）ふん！
あの本のよさは ガキには分からん
Humph! Like a kid could understand
how great my books are.
And...
（ナルト）でもって 酒 女 金
Booze, women, money.
忍しのびの三禁をトリプルで破る
とんでもねえじじい
He's an outrageous old man who indulges
in these three items forbidden for shinobi!
（自来也）こら 師匠に向かって
なんちゅう言いぐさだ
Hey, that's no way to
talk about your master.
I taught you the Rasengan, after all.
螺旋丸だって
わしが教えてやったんだぞ
If you're going to talk like that, then pay me
back the money you took from me.
（ナルト）へえ
んなこと言うなら あんときの金
さっさと返してくれってばよ
Hey, he's gone!
Damn it!
って いねえし
クッソ 逃げられた
He ran away!